Noman Naseer

Electrical Engineer

Cell#: 0331-617-1700

Email: noman.naseer333@gmail.com Address: Gujranwala, Pakistan

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nomannaseer333



Profile

Electrical Engineer having more than one year of Training and Internship experience in multinational and national organizations like NESTLE, GEPCO and NTDC. With an ambition to be a part of a leading organization and give my best in team progress. A visionary individual interested in planning and designing.

Education

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering (PEC# Elect/68496)

CGPA 3.35/4 2013 - 2017

Government College University, Lahore, Pakistan

F.Sc. (Pre-Engineering), 1st Div 2011 - 2013

GIFT College of Sciences, Gujranwala, Pakistan

Matric (Science), 1st Div 2009 - 2011 ST Marks High School Daska, Pakistan

Experience

Associate

June 2018 - July 2018

Nestlé Pakistan Limited, Sheikhupura Factory

Nestlé Pakistan Ltd. is a subsidiary of Nestlé S.A., a company based in Switzerland. Packing plants of multiple products are installed in Nestle Sheikhupura Factory. It was a project-based Associate Program and my project was 'Upgradation of Single Line Diagram of Nestle Sheikhupura Factory'.

- Learned about the power generation through diesel turbines and their maintenance schedule
- Note and upgrade the step-down transformers and breaker scheme on SDL
- Worked on the tagging pattern of HT/LT breakers and distribution panels
- Coupling and cabling of newly installed breaker panels

Trainee Engineer

July 2017 – June 2018

Gujranwala Electric Power Company, Gujranwala, Pakistan

GEPCO is a public-sector company and subsidiary of WAPDA. It provides services of electricity distribution in Gujranwala division. Got an opportunity of training in GEPCO and worked in the subsequent departments to understand the power distributing system including

- Metering and Testing: Worked on testing of faulty energy meters and reclamation of distribution transformers
- Power Distribution Operation: Working principle of distribution transformer and billing of consumed energy units at consumer-end
- Grid System Construction: Construction of 132KV transmission lines, switchyard and installation of power transformer
- Grid System Operation: Working principle of power transformer. It's protection and maintenance.

Intern

June 2016 - August 2016

National Transmission and Dispatch Company Limited, WAPDA House, Lahore, Pakistan

NTDCL is a public-sector company and subsidiary of WAPDA which provides services of transmission and dispatch of power from power generation to power distribution companies. Got an opportunity of six weeks Internship in NTDCL where

- In first three weeks, appointed at 220KV grid station Kot-Lakhpat, Lahore. Learned the entire grid system operation including working and protection of step-up power transformer
- Last three weeks were spend in Designing Department of *WAPDA House*, *Lahore*. That was responsible for the designing of new power grid stations and tendering of switch yard equipment. Note flaws in their managerial work and gave suggestions to improve them

Project

Development of Human Robot for Real Time Explosive Detection

My Final Year Project was a bi-pad robot which was capable to detect any explosive device and give the indication to bomb disposal squad in control room. This project was funded by National ICT R&D Fund. Application of this robot are

- Save breathes during explosive detection
- Used to monitor the explosives in public and remote areas

Courses

AutoCAD

Oct 2017- Dec 2017

- Short course of AutoCAD from TEVTA, Light Engineering Service Center, Gujranwala

Professional PLC

November 2017

 1 weeks training of Professional PLC from Electrical Engineering Solutions Int. Johar Town, Lahore

Certificates

- **Certificate of Award:** Chief Event Organizer on Cultural Theme Day 2016
- **Certificate of Award:** Participating in Annual Project Exhibition 2015
- Certificate of Participation: International Youth Leaders Conference Pakistan 2014